NICHOLAS A. FICETO

Boston, MA 310-924-5141 (***Currently abroad in Taiwan: +886-977-399-267) nicholas.ficeto@tufts.edu

Summary

Highly curious and driven with a passion for consumer analytics and brand strategy, particularly within the nexus between Western/East Asian markets. I am constantly imagining ways to blend experience with programming and analytics software with a creative edge to produce both engaging and analyticallybacked results.

Education

2014 - 2018 **Tufts University**

Economics (B.A.), Computer Science (minor)

Feb 2017 - Jun 2017 National Chenghchi University (國立政治大學)

CIEE: Business, Communications, and Political Economy

Currently studying abroad in Taipei, Taiwan through a university-affiliated business program. Enrolled in an intensive intermediate Mandarin course to hone language abilities to an advanced speaking level and gain reading proficiency.

Skills

C++, Python

Several years coding experience, comfortable working with data structures.

STATA

Ability to analyze and interpret data using econometric statistical principles, as well as

create visual representations of data.

Web Design (HTML, CSS, jQuery, CSS

Frameworks)

Working knowledge of web design (see my website).

Microsoft Office

Excel, Powerpoint, Word

Writing/Public Speaking

Strong oral and written communication skills. Auditioned and selected to be high

school graduation speaker.

Mandarin Chinese, Spanish

Limited working proficiency in Mandarin, Full working proficiency in Spanish

Work experience

Mar 2017 - Present English Language Teacher

The Affiliated High School of National Chengchi University

Hired as an English language teacher to middle school students of a top rated high school of Taiwan. Responsibilities include crafting and implementing lesson plans on a weekly basis for 15 students in

order to accelerate their English speaking and listening abilities.

Oct 2015 - May 2016

Analyst

Tufts Financial Group

Investigated the structures and analyzed the stock behaviors of major companies within both real estate and consumer cyclical sectors. Actively partook in the pitching of multiple stocks to a panel of other analysts, who ultimately decided to add these stocks to the organization's investment portfolio.

Jul 2015 - Jan 2017

Front-Of-House Operations

PRESSED Boston

PRESSED is a juice bar in Beacon Hill, rated "Best of Boston" in 2015 by Boston Magazine. Responsibilities include cashier duties, preparing shakes/food, and assisting in production of cold-pressed juice.

Sep 2014 - Dec 2014

Student Fundraiser

RuffaloCODY

Worked at a call center to solicit donations from alumni, parents, and other individuals associated with Tufts University to fund programs in several departments including financial aid, building renovations, and various academic resources. Achievements include the raising of several thousands of dollars of aid, as well as the acquisition a new donor with a \$1,000 pledge (very rare).

Portfolio

I have written a number of articles exploring the intersection of consumers and technology, and the economic implications of such. See writing samples and research (magazine and academic) on my personal website: laohio.github.io